<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.2/docbookx.dtd">
<?altova_sps C:\Programme\Altova\Authentic2008\sps\Template\Publishing\DocBook.sps?>
<book>
  <bookinfo>
    <title revision="0.0.4.1">Media Encoding Cluster</title>

    <author>
      <firstname>Jan</firstname>

      <surname>Hoelscher</surname>

      <affiliation>
        <orgname></orgname>
      </affiliation>

      <email>info@esblab.com</email>
    </author>

    <pubdate>12.03.2008</pubdate>
  </bookinfo>

  <chapter>
    <title>About Media Encoding Cluster</title>

    <para>The Media Encoding CLuster is a Programm which can be used to Encode
    Media Files Distributed over Nodes that reduces the Encoding Time.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Motivation</title>

      <para>Video encoding is highly processor intensive. While the processing
      power available on standard PCs is continually increasing, so is the
      complexity of modern audio/video codecs. The Media Encoding Cluster uses
      a peer-to-peer network as a substrate for sharing the processing power
      of regular PCs for the purpose of encoding video. This allows nodes the
      easy construction of video encoding farms from cheap standard
      PCs.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Architecture</title>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Generation of process units</emphasis> -
          the source video file is split into x chunks, where x is the number
          of reference Frames in the video.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Distribution and encoding</emphasis> -
          encoding specifications and Media data are sent to each participant
          node, which decode and encodes the process unit.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Recombination</emphasis> - encoded
          process units are returned to the distributing nodes and reassembled
          into a complete encoded video. If process units are not returned due
          to node failure, they are resubmitted to the network for encoding.
          This process repeats until all work units are received by the
          distributing node and reassembled.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <para></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Why using Media Encoding Cluster</title>

      <para>If you want to reduce Encoding Time per Media File!</para>

      <para>If you want to Encode Files in a Batch!</para>

      <para>If you want to have a Fault tollerant and allmost uptime
      Infrastructure for your Media Services!</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Which Operting System for using Media Encoding Cluster</title>

      <para>It is currently running under Windows XP, Linux, MacOsx
      10.5</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>What do i need for running the Media Encoding Cluster</title>

      <para>You need only the Download Package from http://codergrid.de</para>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Installation</title>

    <section>
      <title>General</title>

      <para>On the Windows and Mac OS X platforms the Media Encoding Cluster
      is installed using an installer. On Linux, Solaris and other Unix based
      platforms, the software is installed using a self extracting binary
      installer.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>System requirements and languages</title>

      <section>
        <title>Supported operating systems</title>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Windows XP with Service Pack 2</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Linux</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Mac OS 10.5</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Hardware requirements</title>

        <para></para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>3.2GHz Intel® Pentium® 4 processor (dual Intel Xeon® or
            faster recommended)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>2GB of RAM (4GB recommended)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>1Gb Ethernet card</para>

            <para>Note: When you want to use Distributed Encoding then you
            need Network connections between the Distributed Encoding
            Nodes</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Language versions</title>

        <para>This product is available in the following languages:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>English</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Windows</title>

      <para>To install Media Encoding Cluster on Windows, double-click the
      installer file and follow the instructions on the screen.</para>

      <para>To uninstall, choose Uninstall Media Encoding Cluster from the
      Start&gt;Programs&gt;Media Encoding Cluster menu.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Linux and Unix Systems</title>

      <para>To install the server on Linux and Unix based systems, such as
      Solaris, open a terminal window. Download
      MediaEncodingCluster-Linux-xxx.sh (xxx is a placeholder for the version)
      to any directory, and execute the self extracting installer: sudo chmod
      +x MediaEncodingCluster-Linux-xxx.sh sudo
      ./MediaEncodingCluster-Linux-xxx.sh You will be asked to agree to the
      End User License Agreement.</para>

      <para>The self-extracting installer will install the files in the
      current directory. The server will be installed as the root user.</para>

      <para>To uninstall: delete the installation directory of the Media
      Encoding Cluster</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Default TCP Ports</title>

      <para>Before using the Media Encoding Cluster it is important that you
      open the following ports on your firewall. The table below represents
      the defaults ports used by Media Encoding Cluster. All of these port
      numbers are configurable through the configuration UI described later in
      this document.</para>

      <table>
        <title>TCP Ports</title>

        <tgroup cols="2">
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>Web Administration</entry>

              <entry>8080</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>Client - Server</entry>

              <entry>20200</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Starting and Stopping the Server</title>

    <para></para>

    <section>
      <title>Windows: Command Prompt</title>

      <para>On Windows, Media Encoding Cluster can be started and stopped from
      a DOS command prompt, from the Start menu or from the Windows Services
      administrative tool. To start the server from a DOS command prompt, open
      a DOS command prompt. Change directory (cd) to the bin directory of the
      server installation. The default location for this folder is: cd
      MECINSTALLDIR\bin To start the server, type in .\mhive -r and hit
      return. The startup contains all the server logging statements. To
      shutdown the server hit "ctrl-c" on the console window. The server can
      also be started and stopped from the Start menu using the Server Startup
      and Server Shutdown menu items in the Programs&gt;Media Encoding Cluster
      program group.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Windows: Service</title>

      <para>To start the server as a Windows service, open the
      Settings&gt;Control Panel&gt;Administrative Tools&gt;Services
      administrative tool and locate the Media Encoding Cluster entry in the
      list. Next, right click on the entry and select Start from the context
      menu. To stop the server select Stop from the same context menu. To
      configure the service to run each time Windows restarts, select
      Properties from the right click context menu, set Startup type to
      Automatic and click the OK button to close the dialog.</para>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Configure the System</title>

    <para></para>

    <section>
      <title>Configure the System</title>

      <para>the configuration is started, when you access the admin page the
      first time, you will be guided through the configuration steps. The
      Configuration will setup internal database and write the essential
      config Files.</para>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Encoding my first Files</title>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Create a Profile like the existing "test" Profile, please be
        carefull when entering data, wrong data may crash the server and the
        client</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Create a Watchfolder, selecting a Directory from which the Files
        come to Encode, select a Directory to write the Encoded Files to and
        select a Profile in which the Source Files will be Encoded to.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>thats all, every 10 sec. the Watchfolder will searched for new
        Files, new Files will be visible in the Files Section under Imported
        Files.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>under the Encodings Menu you can see the Encoding Processes and
        in which state there are</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Administrating the System</title>

    <para></para>

    <section>
      <title>Main Concept of the Media Encoding Cluster</title>

      <para>The Media Encoding CLuster is mainly used to Transcode multiple
      Media Files from one Format into an other Format, these formats will be
      described by a Profile. To Transcode one File into an other Format, it
      will be performed over some Watchfolder, watchfolders will be
      permanently scanned and new Files found in these folders will be
      imported into the Cluster, these watchfolder can be connected to a
      Profile, a Profile is mainly the Target Format in which these files will
      be encoded to. The Watchfolder have a parameter called Output Folder,
      these folder will be used to write the successfull encoded Files
      into.</para>

      <para>Currently there is no stable Release out from the Media Encoding
      Cluster.</para>

      <para>All Input made by the Users will not Checked and can cause a crash
      of the Software</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Create a Profile</title>

      <para></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title></title>

      <para></para>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>FAQ</title>

    <para></para>

    <section>
      <title>do i need additional software</title>

      <para>no, there is no need to install additional software to run the
      Media Encoding Cluster.</para>

      <para>You can try put some configuration issues to connect to
      mysql</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>i need Help, what can i do</title>

      <para>look at our Forum, we look frequently into and Answers the
      Question in that</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>what can i do when the Software crashes</title>

      <para>in the base installation dirextory there is a dmp directory, in
      that there are .dmp files that can be uploaded to us. The Dump Files
      containing no personal Information, there are only a Stack dump fro the
      crashed Process and some additional Information about the Hardware
      architecture from the running System.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>is the Software Production Ready</title>

      <para>No! We are in the beginning time to distribute the Software, there
      are many unknown Bugs in there, that can result in an unknown behavior of
      your System.</para>
    </section>
  </chapter>
</book>
