<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
	]><chapter lang=""><abstract><para/></abstract>Hoelscher <para>Media Encoding Cluster</para><para>About Media Encoding Cluster</para><para>The Media Encoding CLuster is a Programm which can be used to Encode Media Files Distributed over Nodes that reduces the Encoding Time.</para><sect1><title>Motivation</title><para>Motivation</para><para>Video encoding is highly processor intensive. While the processing power available on standard PCs is continually increasing, so is the complexity of modern audio/video codecs. The Media Encoding Cluster uses a peer-to-peer network as a substrate for sharing the processing power of regular PCs for the purpose of encoding video. This allows nodes the easy construction of video encoding farms from cheap standard PCs.</para></sect1><sect1><title>Architecture</title><para>Architecture</para><orderedlist><listitem><para>Generation of process units - the source video file is split into x chunks, where x is the number of reference Frames in the video.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Distribution and encoding - encoding specifications and Media data are sent to each participant node, which decode and encodes the process unit.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Recombination - encoded process units are returned to the distributing nodes and reassembled into a complete encoded video. If process units are not returned due to node failure, they are resubmitted to the network for encoding. This process repeats until all work units are received by the distributing node and reassembled.</para></listitem></orderedlist><para/></sect1><sect1><title>Why using Media Encoding Cluster</title><para>Why using Media Encoding Cluster</para><para>If you want to reduce Encoding Time per Media File!</para><para>If you want to Encode Files in a Batch!</para><para>If you want to have a Fault tollerant and allmost uptime Infrastructure for your Media Services!</para></sect1><sect1><title>Which Operting System for using Media Encoding Cluster</title><para>Which Operting System for using Media Encoding Cluster</para><para>It is currently running under Windows XP, Linux, MacOsx 10.5</para></sect1><sect1><title>What do i need for running the Media Encoding Cluster</title><para>What do i need for running the Media Encoding Cluster</para><para>You need only the Download Package from http://codergrid.de</para><para>Installation</para></sect1><sect1><title>General</title><para>General</para><para>On the Windows and Mac OS X platforms the Media Encoding Cluster is installed using an installer. On Linux, Solaris and other Unix based platforms, the software is installed using a self extracting binary installer.</para></sect1><sect1><title>System requirements and languages</title><para>System requirements and languages</para><sect2><title>Supported operating systems</title><para>Supported operating systems</para><orderedlist><listitem><para>Windows XP with Service Pack 2</para></listitem><listitem><para>Linux</para></listitem><listitem><para>Mac OS 10.5</para></listitem></orderedlist></sect2><sect2><title>Hardware requirements</title><para>Hardware requirements</para><para/><orderedlist><listitem><para>3.2GHz Intel® Pentium® 4 processor (dual Intel Xeon® or faster recommended)</para></listitem><listitem><para>2GB of RAM (4GB recommended)</para></listitem><listitem><para>1Gb Ethernet card</para><para>Note: When you want to use Distributed Encoding then you need Network connections between the Distributed Encoding Nodes</para></listitem></orderedlist></sect2><sect2><title>Language versions</title><para>Language versions</para><para>This product is available in the following languages:</para><orderedlist><listitem><para>English</para></listitem></orderedlist></sect2></sect1><sect1><title>Windows</title><para>Windows</para><para>To install Media Encoding Cluster on Windows, double-click the installer file and follow the instructions on the screen.</para><para>To uninstall, choose Uninstall Media Encoding Cluster from the Start&gt;Programs&gt;Media Encoding Cluster menu.</para></sect1><sect1><title>Linux and Unix Systems</title><para>Linux and Unix Systems</para><para>To install the server on Linux and Unix based systems, such as Solaris, open a terminal window. Download MediaEncodingCluster-Linux-xxx.sh (xxx is a placeholder for the version) to any directory, and execute the self extracting installer: sudo chmod +x MediaEncodingCluster-Linux-xxx.sh sudo ./MediaEncodingCluster-Linux-xxx.sh You will be asked to agree to the End User License Agreement.</para><para>The self-extracting installer will install the files in the current directory. The server will be installed as the root user.</para><para>To uninstall: delete the installation directory of the Media Encoding Cluster</para></sect1><sect1><title>Default TCP Ports</title><para>Default TCP Ports</para><para>Before using the Media Encoding Cluster it is important that you open the following ports on your firewall. The table below represents the defaults ports used by Media Encoding Cluster. All of these port numbers are configurable through the configuration UI described later in this document.</para><table frame="all" id="Tabelle1"><title>TCP Ports</title><tgroup cols="2"><tbody><row><entry><para>Web Administration</para></entry><entry><para>8080</para></entry></row><row><entry><para>Client - Server</para></entry><entry><para>20200</para></entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table><para>Starting and Stopping the Server</para><para/></sect1><sect1><title>Windows: Command Prompt</title><para>Windows: Command Prompt</para><para>On Windows, Media Encoding Cluster can be started and stopped from a DOS command prompt, from the Start menu or from the Windows Services administrative tool. To start the server from a DOS command prompt, open a DOS command prompt. Change directory (cd) to the bin directory of the server installation. The default location for this folder is: cd MECINSTALLDIR\bin To start the server, type in .\mhive -r and hit return. The startup contains all the server logging statements. To shutdown the server hit "ctrl-c" on the console window. The server can also be started and stopped from the Start menu using the Server Startup and Server Shutdown menu items in the Programs&gt;Media Encoding Cluster program group.</para></sect1><sect1><title>Windows: Service</title><para>Windows: Service</para><para>To start the server as a Windows service, open the Settings&gt;Control Panel&gt;Administrative Tools&gt;Services administrative tool and locate the Media Encoding Cluster entry in the list. Next, right click on the entry and select Start from the context menu. To stop the server select Stop from the same context menu. To configure the service to run each time Windows restarts, select Properties from the right click context menu, set Startup type to Automatic and click the OK button to close the dialog.</para><para>Configure the System</para><para><inlinegraphic fileref="" width=""/></para></sect1><sect1><title>Configure the System</title><para>Configure the System</para><para>the configuration is started, when you access the admin page the first time, you will be guided through the configuration steps. The Configuration will setup internal database and write the essential config Files.</para><para>Encoding my first Files</para><orderedlist><listitem><para>Create a Profile like the existing "test" Profile, please be carefull when entering data, wrong data may crash the server and the client</para></listitem><listitem><para>Create a Watchfolder, selecting a Directory from which the Files come to Encode, select a Directory to write the Encoded Files to and select a Profile in which the Source Files will be Encoded to.</para></listitem><listitem><para>thats all, every 10 sec. the Watchfolder will searched for new Files, new Files will be visible in the Files Section under Imported Files.</para></listitem><listitem><para>under the Encodings Menu you can see the Encoding Processes and in which state there are</para></listitem></orderedlist><para>Administrating the System</para><para/></sect1><sect1><title>Main Concept of the Media Encoding Cluster</title><para>Main Concept of the Media Encoding Cluster</para><para>The Media Encoding CLuster is mainly used to Transcode multiple Media Files from one Format into an other Format, these formats will be described by a Profile. To Transcode one File into an other Format, it will be performed over some Watchfolder, watchfolders will be permanently scanned and new Files found in these folders will be imported into the Cluster, these watchfolder can be connected to a Profile, a Profile is mainly the Target Format in which these files will be encoded to. The Watchfolder have a parameter called Output Folder, these folder will be used to write the successfull encoded Files into.</para><para>Currently there is no stable Release out from the Media Encoding Cluster.</para><para>All Input made by the Users will not Checked and can cause a crash of the Software</para></sect1><sect1><title>Create a Profile</title><para>Create a Profile</para><para/></sect1><sect1><title/><para/><para/><para>FAQ</para><para/></sect1><sect1><title>do i need additional software</title><para>do i need additional software</para><para>no, there is no need to install additional software to run the Media Encoding Cluster.</para><para>You can try put some configuration issues to connect to mysql</para></sect1><sect1><title>i need Help, what can i do</title><para>i need Help, what can i do</para><para>look at our Forum, we look frequently into and Answers the Question in that</para></sect1><sect1><title>what can i do when the Software crashes</title><para>what can i do when the Software crashes</para><para>in the base installation dirextory there is a dmp directory, in that there are .dmp files that can be uploaded to us. The Dump Files containing no personal Information, there are only a Stack dump fro the crashed Process and some additional Information about the Hardware architecture from the running System.</para></sect1><sect1><title>is the Software Production Ready</title><para>is the Software Production Ready</para><para>No! We are in the beginning time to distribute the Software, there are many unknown Bugs in there, that can result in an unknown behavior of your System.</para></sect1></chapter>